战狼2  2017
注意有海盗
Attention, pirates alongside!
注意有海盗 进入船舱躲避
Pirates alongside! Take cover. All crew below deck!
再说一遍 注意有海盗
I repeat Pirates alongside!
执行紧急措施
Initiate emergency procedure!
所有船员到船舱躲避
All crew below deck!
紧急措施 红色警报
Emergency positions! Code red! Code red!
所有船员到船舱躲避
Get everybody below deck, now!
所有人趴下
Everyone, get down!
杰克 联合国护卫舰在哪？
Jack, where's that UN convoy?
直升机起飞了 三十分钟到
The chopper's on its way,sir. ETA 30 minutes!
所有人躲避到舱里
Get everybody below deck
我在等俺儿子啊
I'm waiting for my son
我不能让他回来找不着家啊
I need our home for his return!
等警察来了 我看你们还敢不敢拆
Wait till police get here! Let's see how you're going to tear our houses!
想死就别拦着
If they wanna die, then let 'em
婶 嫂子
Mrs. Yu, Mrs.Fei.
我们把小飞送回来了
We brought Xiao Fei home
敬礼
Salute!
告诉新来的 俺们中队的座右铭是啥啊？
Tell these rookies what our motto is
谦虚
Be humble
我来当兵就是为了打仗
I became a soldier because I wanted to be in battles
现在呢 打啥仗啊打仗？
and now, what about the battles?
在家都陪陪老婆孩子多好啊
Much better to be at home with wife and kids instead
我闺女 漂亮吧？
My daughter, she's beautiful, huh?
一个个驴球马蛋的啊
You gang of sumbags!
还真拿自己当回事了 是吧？
You think you're tough, huh?
给我打 都上
Go get them! Get them!
警察同志他有枪
Officer see! He's got a gun!
有枪
a gun!
解放军同志 请你把枪放下
Comrade, put down your weapon!
挺能打是吧？
You're pretty lethal, huh?
咋不弄死我呢？
Well you'd better kill me now,
有不在的时候吧
because you're gone,
你看我怎么弄死他们
I'm gonna make them wish they were dead
嘿
Hey!
冷锋
Leng Feng!
军人 之所以被人尊重
The reason a soldier is respected
不是因为军人两个字
is not because of the uniform he wears,
而是因为军人担负的责任
but is because of the sense of duty he carries
即使脱了军装 职责还在
With or without the uniform, the duty remains
一样会被人尊重
And he continues to be respected
快点
Hey, hurry up!
嘿 冷 我们的英雄
Hey, Leng. There's our hero
感谢你救了我们大家
Thanks for saving the lives of everyone
我们合个影呗？ 没问题
Let's take a picture together. No problem!
谢谢  好的 再见
Thank you! Ok, see you!
再见 保重
Take care, see you!
嘿 老板
Hey, boss!
买点吧 这是好东西  上次塔曼村疫情爆发
Buy some, it's good stuff  There was an outbreak in Taman recently
就因为万吃了这个药材 有四个人活下来呢
Because of consuming this herbs, there were 4 survivors
拜托  不了 谢谢
Please! No, thank you!
帮帮忙吧 考虑一下
Please help please consider
老板
Boss.
中国酒来了
Chinese wine.
这儿
This
嘿  别这样兄弟
Hey, hey. Come on man
好吧 这次就算了
Ok, this one is okay
合作愉快 下次见
Nice one. See you next time.
上来
Get up here!
欢迎回来
Welcome back!
再见
Bye
这个 好东西
This, good for you
能让你不再孤单
You're not alone
二十美元 买一送一
20 dollars. Buy one get one free
我是谁  我的干爹
Who am I?  My godfather
如果干爹把这个告诉你妈妈
If your godfather tells your mother about this,
她会怎么想？ 没收了
what would she think? Confiscated!
开始
Begin!
干爹 干爹 干爹
Godfather! Godfather! Godfather!
哈里 哈里 哈里
Harry! Harry! Harry!
干爹 干爹 干爹
Godfather! Godfather! Godfather!
阿冷 阿冷 阿冷
Leng! Leng! Leng!
谁？
Who?
还有谁？ 还有谁？
Who else? Who else?
你上
Do it, do it
去你的
Fuck it!
你以为你是谁啊？
Who the fuck you think you are?
来吧
Come on!
好啊
Yeah
帕特里克 帕特里克 帕特里克
Patrick! Patrick! Patrick!
我要去边境执行一项任务
I've been sent to the border for a mission
等我回来的时候
When I get back,
希望你能在这个文件上签字
this had better be signed
结婚申请
Marriage Application
为什么当兵？
Why did you join the army?
当兵后悔两年 不当兵后悔一辈子
Join the army, you regret it for two years. Don't join the army, regret it for life.
真话？ 真话
The truth?  That's the truth.
再喝
Drink! again!
龙小云同志
Comrade Long Xiao Yun.
在边境执行任务时不幸遇袭
was attacked while carrying her mission at the border.
在现场 我们发现了这枚子弹
We found this bullet.
再喝
Drink again.
你想听什么？
What do you want to hear?
再喝
Drink!
Again!
你赢了
You win.
我输了…
But I lost...
彻彻底底的输了
I've lost completely.
你跟船已经有一年多了
It's been more than a year since you came on board
从杰尔巴到藻拉纳鲁
During that time, from Djerba to Tolanaro,
大半个非洲的部落长老我都问过
I've asked all the chiefs. More than half of Africa,
都没有见过你的这颗子弹
And nobody has seen that bullet before. peluru itu sebelumnya.
我一定会找到的
I will find it,
哪伯走遍整个非洲
even if I have to scour the entire continent.
亲爱的祖国同胞们
Dear fellow countrymen,
首先我对贝卡村受难的同胞表示沉痛哀悼
my deepest condolences to the families their loved ones during Batchka Village incident
今日早些时候 非法武装组织红巾军表示对贝其卡灭村行动负责
Early today, the red scarf rebel army claimed responsibility for the Batchka Village
我们对这种惨绝人寰的行为强烈谴责
Our government condemns their barbaric behavior.
我们的家园 正在遭受一连串的伤害
Our homeland has been attacked on multiple occasions.
不幸的事接二连三的发生
These are great tragedies.
红巾军的恐怖势力如同疫情一样蔓延
The rebels continue to advance as the country grapples with the Lamanla outbreak.
政府不会坐以待毙 伟大的人民军队誓为家园奋战到底
As your government, we will not back down. The great people's army will fight to the very end.
另外国家设立了疫情隔离区
Quarantine have been set up across the country,
最大范围内控制了疫情造成的伤害
in an attempt to contain the Lamanla outbreak.
国家已经把医疗救助级别和紧急程度设为最高
We have declared a state of emergency.
哎 哥们
Hey, brother
少三张
You shorted me 300 bucks.
轻点儿
Be careful with that.
大家都是中国人
Look, we're both Chinese.
这样好么？
You do this to your own people?
我从上个月十四号下午三点开始
Since 3 pm on the 14th of last month,
就不是中国人了
I am no longer officailly Chinese.
怎么着？ 刚从国内来啊？
What? Fresh off the boat?
看见了么？ 现在这局势
Hear that? In times like this,
就是这个价
that's the price you get.
见过这个么？
Seen this before?
没见过
Nope
有人说在这个国家出现过
I've been told that it came from these parts.
我真没见过
Definitely never seen it.
老板
Hey boss.
你怎么样了？来根烟？
How are you? Smoking?
Tundu
Tundu!
走 走
Go! Go!
别开枪
Don't shoot!
别开枪  他们是好人
Don't shoot! Good people
过去 过去
Go, go, go!
想活的就给我趴下
Get the fuck down or you die!
红巾军必胜  你知道你在跟谁说话吗
Hail the revolution! You're now talking to rebels!
不要骗我 你倒霉了
Don't lie to me. Your luck is down!
红巾军必胜
Hail the revolution!
不不不 快看
No, no, no Guys, look!
必胜
Revolution!
这他妈的是什么？ 不不不
What the fuck is this?! No, no, no
他是政府军的走狗
He's a pro-government rat!
不不不  你在骗我
NO! You lied to me!
不不不 红巾军必胜 红巾军必胜
No! Hail the rebels! Hail the rebels!
妈的
Shit!
Tundu
Tundu!
中国大使馆  去大使馆
Chinese embassy  Let's go to the Chinese embassy.
他们会收留我们的 我们是中国人
They'll take us in. We're Chinese.
那我们怎么办？ 我们该怎么办？
What about us? What're we suppose to do?
他们会收留我们吗？ 很难说
Will they accept us?  Hard to say.
那是我们的国家  所有人跟我走
That's our country. Everybody follow me.
走
Go!
快走
Come on!
不
No!
这边
Here
慢着 慢着 不不 中国人 中国人
Slow down! No, no! We're Chinese
快走  Tundu
Go, go! Tundu!
走 走
Go, go, go!
走狗去死 红巾军必胜
Die! Scum! Hail the revolution!
走狗该死
Die! Scum!
去死
去死吧  把枪放下
Die! Lower your guns!
放下武器
Put down your weapons!
把枪放下 把枪放下
Lower your guns! Lower your guns!
大家暂停
Stand down!
我们是中国人
We are Chinese!
中国和非洲都是朋友
China and Africa are friends!
走
Go
走 快走 走
Go, hurry. Go.
走
Go.
撤
Fall back!
帮忙
Help! Help!
首长 他国战舰已经全部驶离战斗区
Commander, all foreign vessels are leaving the war zone.
前方很危险 我们还要继续进港吗？
The harbor is unsafe. Are you certain about docking?
前进十
Forward 10 knots.
航向二七〇
Set course bearing for 270.
开闸门
Open the gate!
老樊 辛苦了 你们海军来的太及时了
Well done, you got here just in time
现在局势怎么样？ 这个国家的叛乱完全爆发了
What's the situation?  The entire country's in chaos.
我们侨民的生命和财产受到严重危害
The war has destroyed lives of many of countrymen.
你们能不能派兵把他们保护出来
Can you send our troops in to help?
未经联合国允许
Without the UN's authorization,
我方作战人员是不能进入的
our troops aren't premitted  to enter the war zone.
您慢点 六十二号
OK, slow, No.62
来来来 往上走 好
Go go go, Up we go! Nice!
你哪的？这不能上
Where are from? He can't board.
我儿子
He's my son.
我们有票 看
We have tickets. See, look!
三张 七九 八十 八一
Three tickets. 79, 80, 81.
好 七九 八九 三十
Fine then. 79, 80, 81.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们去哪？
Where are we going?
总理先生 你听我说
Mr. Prime Minister, please listen to me.
贵国发生这样的事情 我很遗憾
I'm deeply sorry for what's happening in your country.
但是我相信 你也一定不会忘记
But I believe you have not forgotten about the help,
历史上我国对贵国的援助之情
we provided to your country
我们两国之间的友谊
and friendship between our countries
我相信你也知道
I believe you understand how important
我国援非的陈博士对非洲的重要性
our citizen Dr. Chen is to Africa.
请派兵保障陈博士的安全
Please send somebody to protect his safety.
对不起
I'm sorry,
你们现在只能靠自己了  总理先生
you're on your own this time  Prime Minister
陈博士在哪？
Where's Dr. Chen?
我绝不会
I will never
告诉你的
tell you
我们走
Let's go!
十二年的卧薪尝胆啊
12 years of hard work.
一朝战乱 全他妈没了
One war, and it's all fucking gone
这子弹…
The bullet...
有什么故事么？
what's the story?
Tundu
Tundu!
Tundu 下了船就不能上船了啊
Tundu! If you get off, you can't get back on.
Tundu Tundu
Tundu! Tundu!
站住  对不起 对不起
Stop right there! I'm sorry, I'm sorry
我要我妈妈
I want my mom!
我要我妈妈 我不要去中国
I want my mom, I don't want to go to China!
你看着我  我要我妈妈
Look at me  I want my mom!
相信干爹
I want my mom!
相信干爹  兄弟
Ok? I want my mom! Hey brother
你怎么也下来了？
What are you doing down here?
有一件事情我必须跟你说实话
There's something I have to tell you.
你戴的这个子弹…
That bullet...
我见过 这上面的花纹
I've seen it before. That pattern,
好像是反政府武装那边的一个什么标记
is a symbol used by the rebel forces.
我有一个搞军火的朋友跟我说
An arm dealer friend of mine told me
他们现在已经雇佣了欧洲价最高的雇佣兵
the rebels have hired the most expensive mercenaries out of Europe.
我不管你跟他们有什么恩怨
Whatever grudge you've got against them,
我劝你一句
I urge you,
别去送死  桑库加镇的华资工厂
don't go seeking death. 47 Chinese workers!
还有四十七名中国员工
are still stuck at the Hanbond Chinese factory
更可怕的是五十五公里外
What's worse, Dr, Chen is stuck 55 km
还有援非小组的陈博士
behind enemy lines on a medical relief mission
他可是恐怖分子的头号目标
He's a high value target for the rebel army.
从洛奇诺到圣佛兰已经全面封锁
Everything is in total lockdown from Lochino to St. Francis.
没有联合国的允许
Without UN's authorization,
我方作战人员禁止进入交战区
my troops aren't allowed to enter the war zone.
这次撤侨行动 事关重大
This operation is highly important!
我们必须让所有的中国员工
We have to evacuate those Chinese workers!
还有陈博士安全撤离
and Dr. Chen by all means!
在目前情况下 作战人员禁止进入交战区
Under current circumstances, combat troops are prohibited from entering the warzone!
但我们要坚决完成撤侨
In order to complete the evacuation,
必须要一个人单独完成任务
someone has to undertake the mission alone!
我去  站住
I'll go. Stop right there!
干什么的
What's your purpose?
原中国人民解放军东南军区
Former PLA, South-east region,
特种作战旅 战狼中队
Specail Ops Brigade,  Wolf Warrior squadron,
冷锋
Leng Feng.
这孩子的妈妈就在那家华资工厂
This child's mother is  at Hanbond Chinese factory.
我大概知道那里的位置
I know approximately where it is located.
我保证
I promise you,
我会带你妈妈回来的
I will bring your mom back.
我们已经替你搞定好了
We took care of business now, didn't we?
外交部的汤特使 安德拉亲王 德鲁王子
Ambassador Thomas, King Angola, Prince Drew.
该死的通讯部经理
That goddamn communications manager.
他们都消失了
They're all gone. They all disappeared,
神秘的失踪
real mysterously!
不要用这些破事糊弄我
Stop wasting my time with that crap!
陈博士在哪儿？
Where's Dr. Chen?
啊 耶稣
Ah, Jesus.
告诉他 你刚对我说的
You tell him what you told me.
陈博士
Dr. Chen
在圣佛兰华资医院
is at St. Francis Chinese-invested hospital.
乖孩子
Good boy.
听到了么？
Did you hear that?
那也有可能是你的下场
That could be sound of the future.
我们为什么要收红巾军那帮蠢货的钱？
Sir, Why are we helping these fucking idiots?
欢迎来到非洲伙计
Welcome to Africa, son.
伙计们出发
Alrights, let's move out boys!
我们得到最新消息
From the latest report,
战火已经蔓延到桑萨雷姆港口
the fighting is reaching Semshalemu harbour.
那里等待救援的一千五百三十六名中国同胞的生命
The urgency of the evacuating 1536 Chinese nationals wating there
变得危在旦夕
has just been escalated.
撤侨军舰必须全速赶往
Our vessels are heading over at top speed.
很抱歉 因为是别国交战区
My apologies, because the conflict is on foreign soil,
你这次的行动没有支援
you'll have no reinforcements,
没有盟军 也没有武器
no allies and no weapons.
陈博士 还有四十七名中国同胞
Dr. Chen and 47 Chinese workers,
都带回来
evacuate them all.
我老板交代我
My boss asked me
找陈博士
to find Dr. Chen.
你们没人有任何反应
Nobody wants to do something!
现在 那我只能试试运气了
Now, I have to try my luck.
因为
Because
我有
I have
特殊的眼力
a special vision.
我猜猜…
Let me guess...
你是陈博士吗？
Are you Dr. Chen?
我不是 我不是  你是陈博士吗？
I'm not! I'm not! Are you Dr. Chen?
你是陈博士吗？ 不不不
Are you Dr. Chen?  No, no, no.
你吓到她了 她还是个孩子
She's a child, just a child
我是  不
I am  No
不要
No
我是陈博士
I'm Dr. Chen.
你是陈博士？
You are Dr. Chen?
陈博士怎么没蛋蛋了
Looks like Dr. Chen doesn't have balls.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
我就是  Rachel医生 不
I am Dr. Chen. Dr. Rachel, no!
她不是陈博士
She's not Dr. Chen.
她是非常好的医生
She's a very good doctor.
她救过很多人
She saved so many lives.
天啊 不要
No!
陈博士
Dr. Chen!
papa
Papa!
你刚杀了
You just killed
陈博士
Dr. Chen.
Papa  陈博士
Papa! Dr. Chen!
陈博士是吧？
Dr. Chen, right?
我是樊大使派来救你们的
I was sent by Ambassador Fan to rescue you.
这是我的女儿Pasha
This is my daughter, Pasha.
求你务必保护好她
Please, I beg you, protect her.
陈博士
Dr. Chen!
跟我走
Come with me!
上车
Get in the car!
向东走
Go fast!
你想干嘛？
What are you doing?
你以为我在干嘛？我在救你小命
What do you think I'm doing? I'm saving your ass!
我来开车
Let me drive!
让开
Move!
妈了
What the hell!
掉头
Turn around!
快快快
Go, go, go!
神经
Jesus.
Pasha
Pasha!
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
Pasha
Pasha.
站住
Stop!
你们要粮食吗？我们有粮食
You want food? We have food.
我们有粮食
We have food, okay?
We have food.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
是隔离区受的伤吗？
Is that from quarantine zone?
把药箱递给我
Pasha, can you please hand me the bag?
我说是隔离区受的伤吗？
I said, did you get that in the quarantine zone?
没关系  你别觉得我大惊小怪啊
It's nothing. I'm not overreacting.
没有状况最好
In fact, it's better if I was.
刚才那些人感染的是拉曼拉病毒
Those people back there were infected with the Lamanla virus.
感染者很快就会出现发热
Symptoms include the sudden onset fever,
幻觉 溃烂
hallucinations, lesions,
虚汗等症状 是一种通过接触传播的非常罕见的烈性病毒
cold sweats. It's a fatal virus that's transmitted  through direct human contact.
从发病到死亡 最长五个月 最短四个小时
Upon contraction, death strikes between four hours and five months.
而且到现在 还没有研制出能治愈这种病毒的疫苗
Up until now, no cure has been found.
没事 我买医保了
Don't worry, I'm insured.
你杀了中国人
You're killing the Chinese?
麻烦大了
This is a big trouble.
你为什么杀中国人？
Why are you killing the Chinese?
头儿…  你一直想要得到陈博士
Sir... I thought you wanted Dr. Chen.
恭喜你 你得到他了
Congratulations. You found him.
妈的
Fuck!
我要的是活人
I wanted him alive!
活人
alive!
难道你不知道他对我有多重要吗？
Don't you understand how important it is to me?
妈的
Fuck!
等等
Wait.
这个女孩
That girl.
我喜欢她
I like her.
头儿 我们欧洲总部刚传来面部识别结果
Sir, our facial recognition crew uploaded video of this man fighting off some of the pirates.
这人叫冷
His name's Leng.
曾供职于中国某神秘特种部队
Ex-member of a secretive special ops unit pot of China.
战狼
Wolf Warrior.
伙计们
Boys!
援非医疗小组已被武装分子屠杀
The Doctors Without Borders were killed by armed mercenaries.
陈博士和其他中方医护人员已经牺牲了
The lives of Dr. Cheng and other Chinese medical staff were scarificed.
冷锋同志
Comrade Leng,
你能对你说的话负责吗？
do you stand by what are you're saying?
你能确认亲眼看见雇佣兵枪杀我国医护人员和侨民吗？
Are you certain you witnessed the massacre or our medical team?
我确定
I'm cetain.
在牺牲前 陈博士把他的女儿交给我
Dr. Chen give me his daughter before he died.
一个黑人小姑娘
An African girl.
叫Pasha 还有一个女护士
Her name is Pasha. Oh, and anurse too.
你叫什么？
What's your name?
Rachel Prescott Smith 你可以叫我Rachel
Rachel Prescott Smith. You can call me Rachel.
还有是 Rachel医生 不是护士
Doctor Rachel, I'm not a nurse.
把所有情况立即向樊大使汇报
Report the situation to Ambassador Fan immediately.
是
Yes sir.
首长 我儿子呢？
Commander, may I speak to  my son please?
干爹 我妈妈在哪？干爹 我妈妈在哪？
Godfather, godfather! Where's my mom? Where's my mom?
Tundu 相信干爹
Hey, Tundu, Tundu! Trust me, Trust your godfather.
我现在正在开往汉邦工厂
We are going to Hanbond Chinese factoty
到那里去接你妈妈 OK
to find your mom right now, okay?
谢谢干爹
Thank you, godfather.
冷锋 有一个非常不好的消息通知你
Leng, I have some bad news for you.
红巾军正在大肆毁坏重要的公路
The rebel army is sobotaging all major roads,
铁路以及桥梁
railways and bridges.
就在十分钟以前
As of 10 minutes ago,
从华资工厂通向码头的波尔尼加桥
your only route to the port, the Bowerneja bridge,
已被炸断 我和樊大使正在全力想办法
was bombed. We are formulating an escape plan now.
但现在只能靠你自己了
But untill then, you're on your own.
从现在开始 我们最多只能等你十八小时
Set your watch. The macimum time we can wait is 18 hours.
然后军舰就必须返航
After that, we'll be forced to leave.
非常非常抱歉
my deepest apologies.
我必须对全体侨民负责
I have the responsibility to everyone onboard.
明白
I understand.
你要去华资工厂吗？
You're going to the Chinese factory?
我认为我们更应该去美国领事馆
We should go to the Ameriacn Consulate.
那里有海军陆战队 是全世界最安全的地方
The US marines are stationed there. That's our safest bet.
海军陆战队是世界最好的特种部队
You think the US marines are the best in the world?
他们怎么没来接你啊？
That may be true, but where are they now?
我已经通知过他们了
I've informed the  consulate of the situation.
人呢？
Where are they?
你通知他们的方式是？
Tell me exactly how you informed them?
我＠了他们的推特账号
I tweeted at them on Twitter.
欢迎致电美国领事馆
Welcome to American Consulate.
很不幸 我们已经闭馆了
Unfortunately, we are closed.
妈的
Fuck!
我来的时候各国军舰都已经撤离了
All foreign navy ships have left when I arrived.
当我站在码头上向海面眺望
A I watch them sail away from port.
无数远去的桅杆中
Among the countless departing masts.
我看到一面星条旗
I saw one with the stars and stripes.
停车
Stop the car.
Stop the car!
停车 我要下车 停
Stop the car, I want to get out! Stop!
Rachel
Rachel.
海军陆战队接你来了
Your GIs are here to get you.
我是中国人
I'm Chinese.
我来找Nessa
I'm here for Nessa.
Tundu的妈妈
Tundu's mom.
Nessa
Nessa!
有人吗？
Anyone home?
我是来救你们的
I've been sent here to rescue you.
是樊大使让我来的
By Ambassador Fan himself.
你？
You?
救我们？
Rescue us?
我这有十八杆 AK
I've got 18 AK-47s.
三十枚七九式手雷
30 M79 grenade launchers,
够武装一个加强排了吧？
enough to arm a platoon.
现在一把M1911抵在你头上
I have a M1911 pointed at your head right now.
你他妈怎么救我们啊？
How the fuck are you supposed  to rescue us?
冷 冷 你是不是冷？
Leng, Leng! Are you Leng?
你是不是冷
Are you Leng?
Nessa？ 是 是
Nessa?  Yes, yes, yes!
我儿子怎么样了？ 他很安全
What about my son?  He's safe.
他没事吧？ 他没事
He's okay?  He's okay.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank god!
他没事
He's okay.
妈妈 我没事
Mom, mom, I'm ok, I'm ok!
谢谢老天  妈 我没事 你怎么样
Oh, thank god! Mom, I'm ok!
你在中国军舰上
Because you're on a Chinese warship.
我早就告诉你不要卖毛片
I told you, not to sell that porn.
来了 在非洲绝对找不到这么好吃的饺子
Here we go.You definitely won't find better dumplings in Africa.
这是我从中国带来的大厨
I flew in a chef from China.
亲自给你们做的  谢谢
Fresh, just for you. Thank you.
看什么呢？见过吗？
What are you looking at? Seen one before?
玩过这枪吗？
Ever shot one of these?
这狼啊
This wolf here,
就是我用这枪打的
I killed myself with this gun.
这地图谁做的？
Who drew this map?
这是我指导我们家保卫干事老何做的
I instructed our head of security, Laohe, how to do it.
还有几个地没修改好
It still needs some work.
老何 来 过来一下
Laohe, come here for a second.
从A区到D区
Sector A to Sector D.
这个地我已经说过很多遍了
I've told you so many times.
为什么没有修改过来
Why isn't it done yet?
马上就改  老何
I'll get on it right away. Laohe,
赶紧拿笔记一下
write it down quickly.
你还保安队长 这要是实施起来出了问题
As our head of security. What if something happens during the operation?
怎么办？
Then what?
男人就该玩这个
This is a real man's toy.
别怕 从现在开始你的安全
Don't be afraid. From now on, your safety
由我来负责  冷 谢谢你
will be my responsibilty. Leng, thank you!
别客气  非常感谢
You're welcome. Thank you so much!
别客气
You're welcome.
谢谢你
Thank you.
小宝贝 这个特别好吃
Hey, kiddo. It's super yummy
试一下
try this.
你这孩子  没事 干嘛呢你？
Hey! You brat! I'm fine. What's the big deal?
人这孩子挺可爱的
I think she's kind of cute.
好消息
Good news.
樊大使打来的电话 明天上午七点
Ambassador Fan just called. Tomorrow 07:00 AM,
联合国一架救援直升机
A UN rescue helicopter
准时在工厂降落 帮助我们撤离
will be landing at this factory to evacuate us.
一架？
Just one?
各位请注意
Attention please.
所有人
Everybody.
所有人听我说
Everybody listen to me.
大家都安静
Quiet down everyone.
听我说 所有中国人全都站到这一边儿
Listen to me. All Chinese employees, stand on this side.
我们只带中国人 第一批管理层优先
We are only taking Chinese people. Management goes first.
我带大家走
I will lead the evacuation.
明白吗？所有非洲人站在这边
Is that clear? All the Africans please stand this side, please.
明白了吗？
Clear?
哈里
Harry.
不 老板  拜托
No, boss, no. Please.
开始动起来
Come on, come on.
动起来
Get moving.
还有呢？都往那边去 往那边去
Anyone else? Come, move. That side. That side.
你怎么回事啊？ 俺老婆她怀孕了
What are you doing?  She's my wife. She's pregnant
你看看
Look
还有中国人吗？
Any more Chinese?
Any other Chinese?
老林 你给我听好了
Lin, listen to me.
都是我们家员工
Everyone here is my employee.
我都要带走
I'm taking them all with me.
怎么带啊？
How?
别停下来 别停下来
Come on, come on! Don't stop, get moving.
这边是
Get moving. For this side,
非洲同胞
Fellow African.
这边是 中国人  我老婆嫁给我了
Chinese people, this side. She married me.
就是中国人 我要把她带走
so she's is one of us.
走 走
Move, move.
你…
You...
没事 你就站那吧 这儿挺好
Fine, stay there. There's perfect.
来来来 男士们动一动
Come on! Come on! Guys, guys please, please move.
请站倒那边
Stand that side, please.
非洲同胞们 拜托
Please, African friends.
相信我
Trust me.
来 快一点
Come on, hurry uo, get moving.
你滚开 你滚开  别碰我
You want to be on this side, yeah?  Fuck off, bro!
怎么了？
What's up?
为什么？
Why?
中间给我让出一条线来
Give a line down the middle.
我要看清楚一道分界线
I want to see a clear boundary line.
Show me the line, please.
一道分界线
I brought the helicopter.
大家听我的
I call the shots.
明天大家一起走
Everyone leaves tomorrow.
妇女儿童上飞机
Children and women leave with the chopper.
男人跟我走
The men will follow me on foot.
所有人
Everybody.
我们一起走
We leave together.
老师傅 门口那口袋
Old timer, the defensive formation out front,
您布的吧？
that was you, right?
你也不错
You're not bad yourself.
原中国人民解放军 西南军区十四集团军
Former People's Liberation Army of China, 14th Corps, South-West region,
侦察连连长 何建国
Recon Company Commander, He JianGuo.
原中国人民解放军 东南军区特种作战旅
Former People's Liberation Army, Special Ops Birgade, South-East region,
战狼中队 冷锋
Wolf Warrior Squadron, Leng Feng.
班长好
At your service.
敬班长
Drink in your honor.
这些人一小时前
An hour ago, these people
还不知道能不能活到明天
didn't know if they'd live to see tomorrow.
怎么那么开心啊？ 这帮黑哥们
Why are they so happy?  Our African friends,
无论什么战争啊
it doesn't matter if it's war,
瘟疫啊 贫穷啊
disease or poverty,
你只要给他们一堆火 他们立刻就这样
once they're around the bonfire, all their cares go away.
非洲啊 吃的好
Africa. Great food.
景好
Nice scenery.
姑娘好
Hot women.
嘿
Hey.
干杯  干杯
Cheers. Cheers.
我不愿意一辈子活在我爸的光环之下
I don't want to ride my father's coat tail all my life.
你看看这多好啊
I love this place!
有狮子有鳄鱼
Lions, crocodiles,
有AK 有狙
AK-47s, sniper rifles,
有和平地带一辈子都听不到的炮火之声
and the melody of gunfire you can't get in a peaceful country.
那是这个世界上最美妙的声音
That's the most wonderful  sound in the world.
你知道今天Pasha为什么咬你吗？
Do you want to know why Pasha bit you today?
因为他爸爸就是被你喜欢的AK打死的
Because her father was killed AK-47s you so adore.
如果这个是你
If this were you,
你还觉得美妙吗？
would you still thinl it's wonderful??
天呐 你看
Oh man, look at this.
好大一个晚会
That's a big party.
我太喜欢了
I love these things.
瞧他们的样子
Look at them.
妈的
Fuck!
Pasha
Pasha!
妈的
Shit!
放开我
Let me go!
把那个老兵除掉 雅典娜干掉那个老家伙
Take out the veteran. Athena,take out the old man.
待在这儿
Stay here!
放开她
Let her go!
Pasha
Pasha!
我太喜欢他们这个样子了
Like ants when you lift a rock.
妈的
Fuck!
救我
Help me!
我腿受伤了
They got my leg!
你没事儿
You're fine.
妈的
Shit!
走
Go!
走 走
Go! Go!
换弹夹
I need a reload!
走
Go!
你想干什么？
What are you doing, man?
妈的
Fuck!
分头走
Let's split up!
去 去
Go! Go!
妈的
Damn it.
来啊  快走
Come on! Let's go!
Pasha
Pasha.
Pasha你在哪？
Pasha, where are you?
滚开 臭婆娘
Move out of the way, bitch!
快走
Run!
你已经不是军人了
We know you're not a soldier anymore.
他妈的还那么拼干嘛？
What the fuck are you fighting for?
一朝是战狼
Once a Wolf Warrior
终身是战狼
always a Wolf Warrior!
大熊先锋
Bear, you're on point.
雅典娜封住所有出口 这个混蛋我要定了
Athena, cover the exit. I want this son of a bitch.
C 队发现目标 正在追
Team Charlie, spotted target. We are in pursuit.
头儿 B 队发现目标在前方
Sir, Team Bravo has target 12 o'clock.
妈的 这帮蠢货现在让我们撤退
What the fuck? Those idiots want us to retreat now?
我是奥杜将军
This is General Actu
所有人马上撤离
everyone return to base.
马上撤离
Return to base.
老爹 我他妈命令你立即给我滚回来
Big Daddy, I'm ordering you to get the fuck back here now!
你他妈的在做什么？
Hey! What the fuck are you doing?
我他妈的跟你说了多少遍？
I told you so many fucking times
我们不能杀中国人
that we cannot kill the Chinese!
中国是常任理事国
China is a permanent member of the UN Security Council.
我们夺取政权后还要得到中国的承认
And I need them on my side if I am to take political power.
你他妈个蠢货
You fucking asshole!
杀掉冷 抓到Pasha
Kill Leng, and find Pasha,
你将会是这个国家的主人
and you'll be the king of this fucking country
遵命 主人
As you comment, sir!
等等  冷锋
Hold it! Leng Feng!
你到底什么人？
Who are you?
刚一起打完仗你干嘛呢？ 凡哥
We just fought a battle together, what's your deal?  Brither Fan
咱们这本来很安全
we were pretty safe before he got here.
他一来了反叛军就来了
Ever wonder why the rebels show up
你们不觉得很奇怪吗？
after he got here?
他是我儿子的朋友
He's a friend of my son.
他是来接我的
He came here for me.
你之前见过他吗？ 我孩子天天都提起他
Have you met him before?  My son always talks about him.
那又怎样？
So?
我相信他 他今天上午在医院就救过我和Pasha
I trust him! He rescued Pasha and me earlier today at the hospital
之后他也一直在保护我们
He's been protecting us ever since.
如果我没理解错的话
Let me get this straight.
你见他的时候正是你的朋友陈博士死的时候
You met him the same time your doctor friend died?
他一出现就开始死人 而他自己却什么事都没有
People are getting killed around him, while he's unscathed.
朋友 你自己说说吧？
Friend, speak for yourself.
别拦着我
get off me!
拉曼拉  拉曼拉？
Lamanla (Virus). Lamanla?
他得了拉曼拉
He has Lamanla!
老林 他是我朋友
Lin! He's my friend.
他刚才救了我的命
He just saved my life.
他 他们怎么办？
What about them?
他们怎么办 上个月
What about them? Last month,
十公里之外的通讯中心
The comms center10 km away,
一个人得了拉曼拉 最后全厂都他妈死绝了
one person got Lamanla. In the end, the whole place was wiped out.
这可是整厂人的性命啊
Everyone's life is at stake here.
我说的这些话并不是我一个人的意思
look , it is not just my opinion.
不信你可以问他们
Ask them yourself.
我走
I'll leave.
等等
Wait.
你们知道所有得了拉曼拉病毒的人都会很快死去
You all know what will happen to someone infected with Lamanla.
我希望你们永远记得
I hope you'll always remember
这将死的人救了你们所有人
this dying man saved all of you.
你真可耻
Shame on you!
你们所有人都可耻
Shame on all of you!
冷锋
Leng Feng!
你开枪有多大把握  百分之五十
How confident are you with a gun?  So-50%
在我这儿没有那百分之五十
There's no place in my team for so-50%.
您是想让我酒后吐真言呐
Trying to get me drunk so I blurt out the truth?
你会吐真言吗？
Will you blurt out the truth?
会
Certainly.
你喝醉了啥样？
What are you like when you're drunk?
我等你回来请我喝酒
I'll let you buy me drinks when you come back.
你没回来
You're the one who didn't come back.
你回来
Come back to bed.
别闹
Cut it out.
希望我回来的时候
When I get back
你能在这个文件上签字
this had better be signed.
冲上去被打死很容易
It's an easy death when you're on the attack.
难的是背负着内疚和使命感继续活下去
but it's a hard life carrying a survivor's guilt.
是你没回来
But you didn't come back.
你没回来
It's you who didn't come back.
You didn't come back.
到底是谁？
Against who?
昨天跟我们交的手
Who were we fighting yesterday?
你妈妈没告诉你？
Didn't your mom tell you that
小孩子不要玩枪吗？
you shouldn't play with a gun?
冷
Leng!
就是冷 就是他一个人
That was Leng, only him alone.
是我
It was me!
我在这工作之前是个军人
I was in the military before I worked here.
你看看其他人
Does anyone here
像会开枪射击的样子吗？
look like they can shoot?
好啊
Okay.
你醒了
You're up.
可惜陈博士没有看到这一幕
It's a shame Dr. Chen didn't live to see this.
他是全世界唯一发现自愈活体的专家
He discovered the presence of self-healing properties in humans.
陈博士发现有极少数人体内有抵抗拉曼拉的抗体
In extreme rare cases, Lamanla antibodies can be found in patients.
在他无数次和拉曼拉患者的治疗过程中
Among the thousands of Lamanla patients he treated
他偶然发现了一个自愈活体的实例
He chanced upon one such person
而这个自愈活体就是Pasha
And that person is Pasha.
她不是陈博士的女儿 是他的病人
So Pasha's not his daughter, but his patient.
陈博士通过对Pasha血液成分的分析和萃取
From the analysis of Pasha's blood
刚刚研制出一种新药
he created an experimental vaccine.
昨天晚上因为情况紧急
Last night was a dire situation,
我只能在你身上做了一个陈博士曾经设想
so I experimented on you, what Dr. Chen was planning to do.
但是还没来得及做的活体实验
The first human trial that he was hoping for
我把陈博士的新药注射到了你的身上
Injecting you with Dr. Chen's newly synthesized vaccine immunogens
说实话
Honestly speaking,
那个时候我真不知道会发生什么
I didn't know what would happen.
幸运的是
Luckily
上帝站在我们这边
God was on your side.
这个国家人民看到政府对病毒的无能为力极度失望
The population has lost faith in the government to contain the outbreak.
所以 谁得到Pasha
So, whoever takes Pasha
谁就能轻易的掌控这个国家
takes the country easily.
怪不得反政府军一直往追杀我们
That explains why the rebel army is hot on our heels.
我爸爸说十万年前人类走出非洲
My dad said man walked out of Africa 100.000 years ago.
非洲是现代文明的摇篮
Africa is the cradle of modern civilization.
可是当自诩文明的人们再次来到非洲
Yet when the "evolved, civilized" humans returned to this land,
带来的却是苦难
they brought along with them nothing but suffering,
奴役 疾病和战争
slavery, disease and war.
韩国人 冰岛人 斯拉夫人
Koreans, Icelanders, Slavs,
美国人
Americans
那些是中国人 他们都是来自世界各地的
and over there are Chinese. People from all over the world,
像我爸爸一样的人
people like my father.
为了非洲
For Africa
他们付出了自己的青春
they gave their best years.
到最后
In the end,
把自己永远地留在这片土地
they got to remain here for eternity.
她叫什么名字
What's her name?
嗯？
Huh?
那个你忘不了的人
The person you can't seem to forget.
龙小云
Long XiaoYun.
她好幸运
She's lucky
有一个这么爱她的男人
to have a man that loves her so much.
她为什么没有回来呢？
Why didn't she come back?
对不起
Sorry.
把他们当作饺子给我包起来 让他们以为是安全的 明白吗？
I want you to round 'em up like cattle. Make 'em feel safe. You understand me?
收到
Yes, sir.
东边是山区
We got mountains to the west,
西边是雨林 如果他够聪明 就会来这等直升机
we got forests to the east. The only smart place for them to come is right here and wait for the rescue helicopter.
中国佬 你可别死
I sure hope these Chinese people don't die.
能救你的只有我了
I'm about the only thing that can save them right now.
全体集合
Round 'em up.
所有人准备出发 出发 出发 出发 出发
Everybody, let's go! Let's go! Move, move, move!
等我他妈出去了
Wait till I get out of here,
我他妈绝对不会放过这帮孙子
I'm going to settle the score with them.
凡哥
Brother Fan,
别他妈吹牛逼了
cut the fucking bullshit.
怎么出去啊？
How are we going to get out?
再说了 您出去能干什么呀？
And besides, what are you planning to do?
您会什么呀？
What can you even do?
凡哥
Brother Fan,
平时我们都让着你
in normal times, everyone gives in to you.
打起仗来 没人会让着我们
In battle, no one will be giving in to us.
给我闭嘴
Shut the fuck up!
去死吧
Go to hell!
撑得住吗？
Brother, how are you holding up?
比以前差远了
Not as well as back in the day.
你的手是用来救人的 不是用来杀人的
Your hands are for saving lives not taking lives.
这种仗战狼会怎么打
How would Wolf Warriors fight this battle?
走
Go!
你妈妈没告诉你小孩子不要玩枪吗？
Didn't your mom tell you not to play with weap?
你妈没告诉你别欺负熊孩子吗？
Didn't your mom tell you not to fuck with spoiled brats?
走啦
Let's go!
这就是雇拥军与反叛军屠杀我国侨民的证据
Here's evidence of the rebel  army killing our citizens.
收到 我们马上把资料汇总
Transmission received. We will gather up all the information,
让樊大使尽快递交联合国
and have Ambassador Fan submit it to the UN.
明白
Copy that.
另外 当地政府已经向我国正式请求军事援助
oh and one more thing. The local government has critically requested for our military assistance
直升机马上就到
The chopper will arrive shortly
我们等你回家  好
We're waiting for you. Copy that!
你赶紧上飞机  还有很多人需要我帮助
Get on the chopper  There're a lot of people here who still need me.
林志雄
Lin Zhi Xiong!
女人孩子都得上飞机  在这里我不是女人我是医生
Women and childern must get on the chopper. Right now I'm not a woman. I'm a doctor
论救援 我比你专业
The more professional than you when it comes to saving lives.
论保护人我比你专业
But I'm more professional than you in protecting lives!
Pasha 你准备好坐直升机了吗？
Pasha, are you ready to get on the helicopter?
递一些纱布给我
Can you pass me some gauze please?
快上直升机
Get on the helicopter.
你别给我添乱 好不好？
Don't be difficult, okay?
让一下？ 让什么让
Excuse me?  Excuse you my ass!
发生什么事了
Whoa, what was that?
求救 求救
Mayday! Mayday!
我们被袭击 失去尾旋翼
Missile strike! Tail rotor lost!
我还能控制 硬着陆
I have control. Going down!
求救 求救
Mayday! Mayday!
准备迫降
Brace! Brace!
走 走  走
Go! Go! Go!
快跑
Run!
老库房
To the bunker!
快
Hurry!
Rachel
Rachel!
醒醒
Wake up!
Come on! Come on!
Rachel
Rachel!
去找老何
Go find LaoHe!
起身 快点
Get up! Come on!
妈的
Fuck!
快进老库房
Get to the bunker!
走 快 走
Go! Quickly! Go!
走 快
Go! Quickly!
准备
Get ready!
开炮
Fire!
把那个家伙干掉
Kill that motherfucker!
装弹
Reload!
我瞄不到
I can't aim.
这么重  找死啊
This thing's so heavy! You wanna die!?
引信一碰 都得死
Trigger that fuse and it'll kill us all!
开炮
Fire!
哦 好极了
Oh, check it.
下三杠
Three clicks down.
发炮
Fire!
他们找到老库房了
They found the bunker!
目标 左摇
I got it! I got it! To the left.
收到  装弹
Copy that. Reload!
没弹了
We're out!
抓稳了
Hang on!
开炮
Fire!
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch!
妈的 坦克启动
Fuck! Move this fucking thing.
快点
Come on! Come on!
好
Good, good, good.
妈的
Fuck!
看来中国人没有我想的那么懦弱
I guess the Chinese military ain't as lame as I thought.
你少废话
Cut the crap.
走
Go!
快走
Hurry!
不要出来
Don't come out!
立即搜索信号 确定目标位置
Track the signals and verify targets positions!
干爹
Godfather!
妈妈
Mom!
报告 手机位置锁定  报告 目标锁定
Sir, we have triangulated on the phone's position! Sir, targets locked on!
报告 我们得到上级命令  开火
Sir, we recieved orders from COMMAND! Fire!
现在是私人账
Now it's personal.
龙小云
Long XiaoYun.
那是你女人
Is that your girl?
长得很漂亮
She's pretty.
血债… 血偿
Blood... for blood.
别打了
Please don't fight!
你看她们
Look at them.
没错 你将会为这些人而死
You're gonna die for this people.
我就是为他们而生的
I was born for them.
这个世界只有强者和弱者 你们这种劣等民族永远属于弱者
People like you will always be inferior to people like me
你要习惯 你必须习惯
Get used to it. Get fucking used to it.
那他妈是以前
That's fucking history.
你醒了
Welcome back.
前方是交战区 我们过不去了
The war zone is up ahead. We can't get through.
三点方向有不明车队
UNidentified vehicle convoy at three o'clock.
哥
Brother,
把国旗给我
pass me the flag.
开车
Drive.
是中国人 停止射击
It's the Chinese. Hold your fire.
停止射击 是中国人
Hold your fire! It's Chinese.
冷锋
Leng Feng.
首长好  小日子过的挺美的呀
Commander! I see you're enjoying your life.
不想回战狼了吧？
Not planning on rejoining the Wolf Warriors?
离开这里最早的航班
Sir, the earliest flight out of here,
是下星期二 十四点十五分 星期五上午九点
departs next Tuesday at 14:15 by Friday 09:00.
我准时向您报道
I will report for duty sir!
有件事我必须告诉你
There's something I need to tell you...